Guide to the Tom Rankin photographs and papers, 1980-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Sacred Space, 1993, (65 prints)
  - Baptism, Jerusalem M. B. Church, Mound Bayou, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Deacon Fred Davis, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baptism, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Candidate for baptism, fourth week in August, Perthshire, 1989, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Juandra Griffin and Venita Murray, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Prayer after baptism, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Congregation outside Bethlehem No. 2 M. B. Church, Shaw, 1991, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baptism of Cheronda Brown by Reverend Crabtree, Stamps Lake, Perthshire, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Baptism, Moon Lake, Coahoma County, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Candidate for baptism, Mound Bayou, 1990, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, 11x14 inches in 16x20 inch mat ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Other Photographic Work Series, undated, (1 print)
  Series houses prints that do not form part of other established bodies of photographic work in the collection. Original title supplied by photographer.
  - Author Tim McLaurin at home with George, Hillsborough, North Carolina, undated, (black-and-white gelatin silver print, signed, 11x14 inches ) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Manuscripts and Recordings Series, circa 1980-2013, (14 boxes, 1 mp3 file)
  Professional papers, including correspondence, writings, teaching materials, and other documents, stemming from Tom Rankin's long career in teaching and documentary arts, and serving as Director of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University. Includes a digital audio recording of his opening talk on February 27, 2008 at the Duke University Libraries exhibit of his work, Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta. This file has been mounted on the library server and is also available online through the Duke Libraries digital exhibits website. The papers have been given basic processing.
  [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact a reference archivist before coming to use this collection.]
  - Papers and recordings, circa 1980-2013 (Box 10-25)